Guide to the Hawks Family Papers Relating to Business Ventures in the American West
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Hawks Family Papers Relating to Business Ventures in the American West
1854-1899
WA MSS S-2958
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
4.59
(11 boxes)
Hawks Family
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Scope and Contents
Correspondence and financial records of the Hawks family's business ventues in the American West. Correspondence among William E. Hawks, senior, Samuel B. Hawks, William E. Hawks, junior, William S. Hawks, and George M. Hawks documents the family's management of its companies. Also present is extensive correspondence with the family's business partners and financial organizations.
William Edward Hawks (1832-1911)
William Edward Hawks was a resident of Bennington, Vermont who traveled to and conducted business in the American West. Hawks primarily worked in the water works industry; he was an executive with the Monroe Water Works and Light Company, Illinois's Marseilles Water Power Company, and the Raton Water Works Company of Raton, New Mexico.
Samuel Brown Hawks (1862-1899)
Samuel Brown Hawks, son of William Edward Hawks, senior, was a resident of Bennington, Vermont who conducted business in the American West. He managed cattle in Idaho, Montana, and Wyoming and was an executive of the Soda Springs Land and Cattle Company. He also worked in the water industry and was an executive with Louisiana's Monroe Water Works and Light Company, the Monroe Plumbing Company, and the Illinois's Marseilles Water Power Company.
Businessmen -- West (U.S.); Cowboys -- West (U.S.); Waterworks -- West (U.S.); Water-power -- West (U.S.); Water-supply -- West (U.S.); West (U.S.) -- Economic conditions -- 19th century; West (U.S.) -- Commerce; West (U.S.) -- Social life and customs -- 19th century; Businessmen -- West (U.S.) -- 19th century; Cowboys -- West (U.S.) -- 19th century; Hawk family; Hawks, William Edward, 1832-1911; Hawks, Samuel Brown, 1862-1899; Hawks, William S.; Hawks, William Edward, active 1854-1899; Hawks, George M.
- Cattle business records, 1886-1891; 2 (Box 1)
- Idaho business financial records, 1868-1893; 3 (Box 1)
- Soda Springs Land and Cattle Company records and Samuel B. Hawks records, 1883-1892; 3 (Box 1)
- Water works business records, including for the Monroe Water Works and Light Company and the Marseilles Water Power Company, 1861-1899; 5 (Box 2)
- Unsorted business records and correspondence, 1854-1898 (Box 2)
- Unsorted business records and correspondence, 1854-1898 (Box 3)
- Unsorted business records and correspondence, 1854-1898 (Box 4)
- Unsorted business records and correspondence, 1854-1898 (Box 5)
- Unsorted business records and correspondence, 1854-1898 (Box 6)
- Unsorted business records and correspondence, 1854-1898 (Box 7)
- Unsorted business records and correspondence, 1854-1898 (Box 8)
- Unsorted business records and correspondence, 1854-1898 (Box 9)
- Unsorted business records and correspondence, 1854-1898 (Box 10)
- Unsorted business records and correspondence, 1854-1898 (Box 11)